Guide to the Richard William Weiland Papers SC0855
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Computers other than Microsoft, Series 4
  - Presentation Graphics on the Apple Macintosh 1984 (Box 59)
  - Your Commodore 64: A Guide to the Commodore 64 Computer 1983 (Box 59)
  - VIC-1541 Single Drive Floppy Disk User’s Manual 1981 (Box 59)
  - Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid, by Douglas R. Hofstadter 1979 (Box 59)
  - Computer printouts: SORD M200, COMSCN, CONSIO, PERDRV, ACPDAT, DSKDRV – Dec. 1978 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Computer printouts: SQRT, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Computer printouts: RWTRI, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Computer printouts: SIMON, 1970 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Computer printouts: ADAM 752,2662 FACTORIALS 1970 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Computer printouts: LINED, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Computer printouts: EDITX, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 7-8)
  - Computer printouts: UUOPRV, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - PDP10 Reference Handbook 1970 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Third International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence 20-23 August 1973. Advance Papers of the Conference (1 v.) (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - M6800 Microprocessor Applications Manual 1975 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - MOE Microcomputers: KIM-1 User Manual August 1976 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - American National Standard: Programming Language COBOL 1974 (Box 66, Folder 4)
- Research, Series 5
  - COBOL Users Guide - decsystem10 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - BLIS/COBOL v. 3.0 Specifications (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - The COBOL Project Report - May 1982 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Video (Graphics) (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - SMARTERM Intelligent Interface (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Software International (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Personal Accounting Software (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Software Industry News and Notes: July-December 1992 (Box 35, Folder 16-17)
  - Software Industry News and Notes: January-June, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Misc. Writings re: Technology (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - AOL (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - AOL Software, May 1996-December 1998 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Emerald Onramp, June 1996-February 1997 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - CompuServe Internet Services, May 17-19, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Teleflex (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Work Notes 1988-1991 (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
  - Work Notes 1992-1995 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Work Notes 2000-2003 (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - Software 2001-2006 (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - Software 2001-2006 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Software (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
  - iShares (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - PNO (again) (Box 38, Folder 5-6)
  - POP (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - POP Series D, Apr-May 2001 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - POP series E, Jan-Apr 2002 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - PNO and OLP Mid-Nov. 2000-Feb. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - PlanetOut (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - PlanetOut Partners Investor Material (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - PlanetOut Apr-May 2000 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - PlanetOut Prospectus & Reports 2004 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - PlanetOut, 2004 and beyond (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - DQ 1997-98 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - American Management Systems in Perspective (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - HBS Notes 1979-80 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Venture Ideas [clippings, etc.] 2001-2005 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Venture Ideas [clippings, etc.] 2001-2005 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Administration (Clippings re: investment) 1988-99 (Box 40, Folder 2-4)
  - Financial and Business Correspondence/Receipts (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - 1978 World Bank Atlas (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - ValueLine 1991) (Box 40, Folder 7-8)
  - ValueLine 1988 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - ValueLine 1989 (Box 41, Folder 2-3)
  - ValueLine 1990 (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
  - VS II 90.5: Plans, Approach, MSFT, Equity (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - VS II 90.5: Equity (cont'd.), Security, Funds (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - VSII 90.0, S&P 500 (Box 42, Folder 4-6)
  - Stocks: Graphs (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Investment, Winter-Spring 1995 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Prices and Yields Daily, January 1988-June 1999 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Re: Financial (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - 1989 investment research (Box 43, Folder 6-8)
  - 1991 investment research (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - 1991 investment research (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Investments 1995-2000 (Box 44, Folder 3-5)
  - Stock Agreements Sept. 2000 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Investment 2003: Apr-May 2003 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Net worth figures, 2001-2005 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Budgeting [notes, text, computer printouts] 1988 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Budgeting 1988 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Budgeting 1988: CARS (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - General Electric, Fall 1989 and onwards (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Performance [clippings, notes] 1998-2003 (Box 45, Folder 4-6)
  - "Private" Distribution [clippings etc. re estate tax] (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Location II: A Review of "Where to Live?" Ideas During 1988-91 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Real Estate/Housing Clippings (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Real Estate/Housing Clippings (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Press [re investments, business, etc.], 1995-99 (Box 46, Folder 2-4)
  - Cinema 1992-1997 (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
  - Magazine Table of Contents pages (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Writings re: intelligence, Zen (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Opinions (clippings, web printouts, etc. on gay issues) (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Health Issues (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Card files on his charity interests and politics (Box 63)
- Personal Papers, Series 6
  - Personal Accountant (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Corvette brochures (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Personal Car papers and roadmap of Albuquerque area (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Rancho San Joaquin Apartments (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - New Mexico Magazine, November 1976 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Sept-Oct '85: Notes on LA and SF, CA (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Real Estate: "My Home" (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - The Art of the Hot Comb [illustrated for men's use] (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - "Pride" and the death of Felix "Chip" Mark Kehoe (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Wellness 1994-2005 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Wellness 1994-2005 (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
  - Physical Training and Health, 2002-2003 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Sculptra FAQ (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Diets (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - "Muscle" (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Wellness 1998-2005 (Box 48, Folder 7-8)
  - EXPLO (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Resumes - Oct 1985 and early 1980s (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Headstone Photo (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Ric's Address Book (Most Current) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Ric's Funeral and Will (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Estate Planning Proposal for Ric Weiland (Merrill Lynch Trust Company) (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Pers. Acct. Accounts and Setup for Ric W., 1983 and 1987 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Distribution 2000-2003 (Autumn 2005) (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Philanthropy Records 1996 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - 1997 Philanthropy Records (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - 1998 Philanthropy Records (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - 1999 Philanthropy Records (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - 2000 Philanthropy Records (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - 2002 Philanthropy Records (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Assets 1983 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Assets 1984 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Assets 1985 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Assets 1986 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Assets 1987 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Assets 1988 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Assets 1989 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Assets 1990 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Assets 1991 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Assets 1992 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Assets 1993 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Assets 1994 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Personal Matters (Up Until HBS) (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - 1986-87 Notes (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Highlights and Insights 1988 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Highlights and Insights 1989 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Highlights and Insights 1990 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - 2nd half 1985 diary excerpts (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - First half of 1986, Diary Excerpts (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Diary Writing - Spring 1988 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Personal Diaries - some ordered (Box 52)
  - Personal Diaries - unordered (Box 53)
  - Weiland's personal cards (Box 63)
- Photographs, Series 7
  - Printer Tests for portrait with dog (photos and notes) (Box 33, Folder 12-13)
  - Confirmation (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - England by Mart and Dick, 1974-06 (Box 61)
  - England, Italy, Winter 1974 (Box 61)
  - Russia, Paris, Venice, Yugoslavia, Greece, 1974-03 (Box 61)
  - Autria, Paris, Scotland, Cliveden, Spring 1974 (Box 61)
  - Holland, Germany, Paris June 1974; New York City, Washington, DC Summer 1974; others Fall 1974-Summer 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 61)
  - Williamsburg, Redondo Beach (Box 61)
  - Snow in ABQ (Albuquerque?), Winter 1977 (Box 61)
  - Dodge Dart with Stanford bumper stickers (Box 61)
  - Stanford graduation, taken by RHW, 1976-06 (Box 61)
  - TT ("tacky tourist") cruise (Bob B & Ric W, Chuck Pishke, Rick Chaiko, Steve Myman), 1984-08; 1 film reel(s) (8mm) (Box 61)
  - Holland, Germany and Paris by Mart & Dick, 1974-06 (Box 61)
  - Weiland photo album, 2006-12 (Box 61)
  - Album from trip to Stanford University and San Francisco, 2004-01 (Box 61)
  - Weiland receiving his Stanford diploma, 1976-06 (Box 61)
- Audiovisual Materials, Series 8
  - Jan 31 / Feb 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Feb 14 / Feb 16, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Feb 21 / Feb 23, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Feb 26 / Feb 28, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Mar 2 / Mar 5, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Mar 7 / Mar 11, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Mar 14 / Mar 16, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Max Sex, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 63)
  - Weiland family films of the 1960s (49 minutes), 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 61)
  - CBS coverage of moon landing, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 61)
- Memorabilia, Series 9
  - Microsoft 3-ring binders (2) (Box 64)
  - Fraternity (?) paddle [no insignia, but signed by 25 guys] (Box 64)
  - Macrame belt (Box 64)
  - Stanford pennant, red felt with University seal (Box 64)
  - ID from Comdex/Spring '87 (Box 64)
  - Apple computer decals (Box 64)
  - Stanford School of Engineering decal (Box 64)
  - Sam Nunn, US Senate, letter opener with leather case (Box 64)
  - Groucho Marx nose-and-glasses mask (Box 64)
  - Black tassle with "76" tag (Box 64)
  - Microsoft pens and key chain (Box 64)
  - Harvard key chain (Box 64)
  - Button: I Made it with the Leader. M/A-COM DCC. DataCom Products Division (Box 64)
  - T-shirt: white with the word "Stanford" (Box 64)
  - T-shirt: grey with "Stanford" and trees (Box 64)
  - T-shirt: blue with the word "Stanford" (Box 64)
  - T-shirt: red, Class of 1976 on front, "Robber Barons?" on back (Box 64)
  - Oversized and framed items: Membership certificate to Founding Grant Society; Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity membership, 1972 (framed); service certificate from Stanford Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Community Center (framed) (Box 65)
- Computer Files, Series 10
  - System 80 Disks, 16 January, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - floppy disks (4), 1990 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Archive and VSII floppy disks, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Investment Research - floppy disks (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - archive floppy disk, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - floppy disk: Backup: Pers. Acct. 4/1, New Gen. 3/28 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Archive: Pers. Acct., New Gen. 5/14 10:00pm (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Pers. Acct. 6/14/88, Basic 3.00 9/30/86, System 3.2, Finder 5.3 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: ARCHIVE 2/91, Pers. Acct. late 1993, New File 4/30/85, QuickBASIC(d) v1.0 8/88, Depreciation 12/17/93 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: ARCHIVE: BASIC(d) 8/85, Finder v4.1 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Pers. Acct. (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: ARCHIVE (office): Pers. Acct. 8/27/85, New Gen. 4/30/85 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Office Archive: Pers. Acct. 5/14/85, New Gen. 4/30/85 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Office Archive: Pers. Acct. 3/29/85, New Gen. 3/28/85 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Archive Aug. 27, 1985: BASIC 8/31, Pers. Acct. 8/27, New Gen. 4/30 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Archive: Pers. Acct. 5/14/85, New Gen. 4/30/85 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Archive: 4/1/85 Pers. Acct., 3/28/85 New Gen. (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Archive: BASIC(d) 8/85, Finder v4.1 (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Accounts for Dr. Browning – final as of 3/6/87. Home Archive (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Copy of April 1 Archive: BASIC 3/13, Dr. Browning 4/1, Ric Weiland 4/1 (RW-1985 was updated 11/23/85 while debugging reference counts) (Box 63)
  - floppy disk: Until 2/1/91, the disks were Bank Archives, stored in a bank (Box 63)
- Philanthropy and Bequests, Accession ARCH-2008-141
  - Booklet: Ric Weiland 1953-2006 Gifts in Legacy [short biography and narrative sections on bequests to organizations] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - amfAR Aids Research: annual report 2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Children’s Hospital Foundation: copies of correspondence re his gifts 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Defense Fund: annual report 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center: publications and copies of correspondence re his gifts, 1988-2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - GLSEN: annual report 2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lakeside School: publications and copies of correspondence re his gifts, 1988-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous: The Advocate, April 8, 2008; Lambda Legal Impact, Summer 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National Wildlife Federation: SUA inquiry letter and printed account of his gift (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Nature Conservancy: (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Pride Foundation: correspondence and other items, 1994-2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pride Foundation: publications, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - In the Life [recipient from Pride Foundation]: correspondence and other items, 1999-2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sierra Club: annual report and financial statements, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stanford University: publications and booklets regarding his contributions, 2008-2010 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - United Way, Tocqueville Society The Book of Leaders, with letter, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Victory Fund: programs and miscellaneous correspondence, 2005-2008 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Weiland's 2001 Philanthropy Records [mostly correspondence] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Weiland's 2003 Philanthropy Records [mostly correspondence] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Weiland's 2004 Philanthropy Records [mostly correspondence] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Weiland's 2005 Philanthropy Records [mostly correspondence] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Mike Schaefer, Philanthropy Records of Weiland’s bequests [mostly correspondence], 2007-2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)